<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Arun Gopinath</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Arun Gopinath</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arungopi.gitlab.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Roller Coaster ride</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2022/</guid><description>Roller Coaster ride “With peaks of joy and valleys of heartache, life is a roller coaster ride, the rise and fall of which defines our journey. It is both scary and exciting at the same time.”
Sebastian Cole</description></item><item><title>Movie barcodes of Dileesh Pothan movies</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2022-12-18-movie-barcode-of-dileesh-pothan-movies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2022-12-18-movie-barcode-of-dileesh-pothan-movies/</guid><description>Movie barcodes of Dileesh Pothan movies Dileesh Pothan is already a rocking star in the Malayalam movie industry for his outstanding movies. Within just three films, he already owns a place in the minds of movie buffs. Subtle details and realistic presentation of stories are popularly known as Pothettan brilliance.His works with Fahad Faasil are a treat to watch. Apart from directorial skills, he is also known for his produced movies.</description></item><item><title>Creating a rainfall forecasting dashboard of Kerala, India. A non-shiny dashboard for all seasons.</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2022-03-03-creating-a-rainfall-forecasting-dashboard-of-kerala-india-a-non-shiny-dashboard-for-all-seasons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2022-03-03-creating-a-rainfall-forecasting-dashboard-of-kerala-india-a-non-shiny-dashboard-for-all-seasons/</guid><description>A non-shiny dashboard for all seasons Ideas and implemenation Let’s dive in Part 1 - Tabulizer helps but.. Part 2 - Flexdashboard and leaflet is a great combo. Part 3 - Automation using Github actions. A non-shiny dashboard for all seasons Dashboards are exciting tools to present an idea in the most human-friendly form available. Ideas are infectious it took some time to fix the theme of my dashboard will be ‘Rainfall forecast of Kerala’.</description></item><item><title>Ripple effect</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2021/</guid><description>Turbulent and peaceful &amp;ldquo;The mind is everything. What you think you become.&amp;rdquo;
Buddha</description></item><item><title>QGIS model to quickly calculate bound box of all polygons in a shapefile</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/qgis_bound_box_model/qgis_bound_box_model/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/qgis_bound_box_model/qgis_bound_box_model/</guid><description>Calculating the boundary box of a large number of polygons in a shapefile in QGIS is discussed earlier in this post. The process itself is tedious and required a support from Microsoft Office. There has been numerous updates arrived in QGIS and several algorithms were incorporated. Keeping this in mind I developed a QGIS model which can create an output with a simple click.
Download this Model and save it in suitable location.</description></item><item><title>Is Cristiano Ronaldo lost his interest in twitter? A fun analysis of tweets of Cristiano Ronaldo using R</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-11-21-a-fun-analysis-of-tweets-of-cristiano-ronaldo-in-r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-11-21-a-fun-analysis-of-tweets-of-cristiano-ronaldo-in-r/</guid><description>A detailed analysis of tweets of famous footballer Cristiano Ronaldo in R Get Ronaldo’s tweets timeline Let’s dive into it. Plotting tweets per months over the time period Bar plot to get more insight Is there any pattern over the months ? What about over the days ? Tweets over the time Retweets v/s Original tweets Text mining - Let’s deep dive into the tweet data What about Hashtags frequency ?</description></item><item><title>Exploratory Data Analysis of Covid 19 data of India</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/data-exploration-of-covid-19-data-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/data-exploration-of-covid-19-data-india/</guid><description>Exploring and visualising Covid 19 dataset of Indian states using R Load required packages Data… Data.. Loading latest shapefile of Indian states Exploratory Data Analysis First reporting case - When ? Where ? Peak active covid case in India - When ? Which day records maximum TPR in India? Highest death rate recorded ? Top 5 states with cumulative confirmed cases ? Least cumulative confirmed cases ? Most deaths - Top 5 ?</description></item><item><title>Convert a bulk of pdf files into images in just two lines of code (Only for linux users)</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-07-31-convert-a-bulk-of-pdf-into-images-in-two-lines-of-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-07-31-convert-a-bulk-of-pdf-into-images-in-two-lines-of-code/</guid><description>Just two lines of code for linux users Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a folder consists of hundreds of pdf files. Your job is to convert it into image format (jpg or png). If you are in a Linux environment, then the solution is pretty simple. Just two lines of code!
In the file manager open the folder containing pdf files. Right-click and select Open terminal (here). Once inside that directory,then you can type or copy and paste the following command in the terminal and press enter:</description></item><item><title>Can you identify this legendary malayalam novel ? A ggwordcloud experiment in R</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/r-wordcloud/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/r-wordcloud/</guid><description>A legendary novel Yesterday out of nowhere the masterpiece novel, which changed the course of Malayalam literature forever pop up in my social media feed. After reading the digital copy (.epub) of the same, the idea for this article came into my mind. All I have for you is “words”.
Create a word cloud using R First of all, load necessary R packages. {readtext} and {tidytext} for load our novel.</description></item><item><title>Convert a shapefile into a interactive online map</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/maps-online/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 17:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/maps-online/</guid><description>Introduction Imagine you have a shapefile (.shp) with you. Now you want to show the interactive map to your colleague. There are two options:
Share your shapefile via e-mail OR
Share as a link (more user friendly). Not everytime you are equipped with ArcGIS or QGIS. Its difficult to open those files in your mobile devices. So a easy link which opens an interactive map will be cool idea to checkout.</description></item><item><title>Detailed map of Kerala assembly elections 2021</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/assembly2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/assembly2021/</guid><description>Kerala assembly election results 2021 The 2021 Kerala Legislative Assembly election was held in Kerala on 6 April 2021 to elect 140 members to the 15th Kerala Legislative Assembly. The results declared on 2 May.
Results in a nut shell Party Seats LDF 99 UDF 41 NDA Nil Total seats 140 This article provides the shapefile containing the details of candidates in each legislative assembly. Shapefile used here are obtained from Kerala Open Data.</description></item><item><title>Extracting the boundary extends of polygons in a shapefile using QGIS and VBA in Microsoft excel</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/bound-extend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/bound-extend/</guid><description>Introduction In this tutorial lets us learn how to extract the boundary limits or bbox values of each polygon in a shapefile using QGIS. First of all, imagine a shapefile consists of some number of polygons. So each polygon can be exactly fit into imaginary rectangles each having upper and lower limits of latitude and longitude values. These four limits will be the boundary for that polygon. Similarly, remaining polygons will also have such boundaries.</description></item><item><title>പെരുങ്കടവിള തദ്ദേശ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പിന്റെ ചില സ്ഥിതി വിവര കണക്കുകൾ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/election2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/election2020/</guid><description>പെരുങ്കടവിള തദ്ദേശ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പിന്റെ ചില സ്ഥിതി-വിവര കണക്കുകൾ 2020-ലെ കേരളം തദ്ദേശ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പിന്റെ ആവേശം ഉൾക്കൊണ്ട് എന്റെ പഞ്ചായത്തായ പെരുങ്കടവിളയിലെ ചില രസകരമായ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പ് വസ്തുതകളാണ് ഈ ലേഖനത്തിൽ. ഈ അന്വേഷണത്തിൽ പഞ്ചായത്തിലെ 16 വാർഡുകളുടെ വിവരങ്ങൾ ആണ് ഉൾക്കൊള്ളിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നത്. ത്രിതല ഭരണ സംവിധാനത്തിൽ മുകൾ തട്ടായ ബ്ലോക്ക് ഡിവിഷനും ജില്ലാ ഡിവിഷനും ഇതിൽ ഉൾപ്പെടുത്തിയിട്ടില്ല .
Total available votes: 20495
പഞ്ചായത്ത് ഭൂപടം
വാർഡുകൾ ഭൂപടം - സർക്കാർ വക
സ്ഥാനാർത്ഥികൾ - ചില രസകരമായ വിവരങ്ങൾ വിവരശേഖരണം കേരളം സ്റ്റേറ്റ് ഇലെക്ഷൻ കമ്മീഷന്റെ വെബ്‌സൈറ്റ് വഴി ഡൌൺലോഡ് ചെയ്തെടുക്കൽ ആയിരുന്നു ആദ്യപടി. പതിനാറു വാർഡിലെയും സ്ഥാനാർത്ഥികൾ അവരുടെ - പേര് , വിലാസം , പ്രായം , പാർട്ടി, ചിഹ്നം, ലിംഗം തുടങ്ങിയ അടിസ്ഥാന വിവരങ്ങൾ ആണ് അതിൽ കാണാനാവുക.</description></item><item><title>Visualising Election Ink in 3D</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/silvernitrate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/silvernitrate/</guid><description>Election day thought I was at the polling station to take part in covid19 election era. As usual, the violet ink marked my participation in the mega event. This ink is a super solution capable of changing the lives of the people. After reaching home, all I want to know is &amp;quot; what is this solution? &amp;ldquo;. The answer is Silver nitrate. According to Wikipedia, the exact composition consists of alcohol and biocides for longevity and to ensure bacteria not transferred from voter to voter.</description></item><item><title>Curated list of amazing websites - Part 1</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/websites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/websites/</guid><description>Amazing websites There are websites which are fun to surf in the web world. Some of them are useful in day-to-day life. But there are some websites which are made with the sheer genius and make us wonder “How they made this?”. So, this is a curated list of such websites Part 1.
WebGL fluid simulation As the name suggests, one can play with fluid simulation all day. It works on any web browser irrespective of their OS platform.</description></item><item><title>Automatically update the titles in your Youtube videos.</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/title_youtube/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/title_youtube/</guid><description>Magic video The idea of changing the title of the youtube video automatically seems insane to me. There is a tutorial about how to achieve this feat is thoroughly done by Amit Agarwaal. The original concept was by Tom Scott. This article is all about the implementation of the same in my video.
Youtube api and Google scripts are primarily responsible for this weird feat. Most of the contents of this article are from labnol.</description></item><item><title>People in space right now - R shiny app</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/iss_live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/iss_live/</guid><description>The idea The inception of fancy R shiny apps in my mind came from the mysterious web algorithm of google I guess. I have to start something. Now, where to start? Suddenly this idea of an R Shiny app which shows the details of International Space Station popup. Ok, that sounds good. But where to start?
The implementation The benefit of the shiny app is the sharing options it provides. Thankfully, the data obtained from api.</description></item><item><title>പൂവാർ ഉയർത്തുന്ന ചോദ്യങ്ങൾ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/poovar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/poovar/</guid><description>കൊറോണ മഹാമാരി ഇവിടൊക്കെ കുടിയേറിയ ശേഷം യാത്രകൾ ഒരു അലങ്കാരം മാത്രമായി പോയോ എന്ന് സംശയം പലരും പറയാതെ പറയുന്നുണ്ട്. ഒരേ സമയം ചിലവും ആരോഗ്യവും മോശമാക്കി ഒരു യാത്ര അത്ര നല്ല തീരുമാനവും അല്ല. എങ്കിലും ഒരു ചെറു യാത്ര നൽകുന്ന ഉന്‍മേഷവും സന്തോഷവും പകരം നൽകാൻ എന്തുണ്ട്. ഇത്തരം സായാന്ഹ യാത്രകൾ നമുക്ക് വളരെ പ്രിയമാകുന്നതും അതുകൊണ്ടാണല്ലോ .
നെയ്യാറ്റിൻകരയിൽ നിന്നും ഒരു മണിക്കൂറിൽ താഴെ മാത്രം യാത്ര വേണ്ടിവരുന്ന ഒരു കടപ്പുറമാണ് പൂവാർ. നദിയും കടലും ഒന്നിക്കുന്ന പൊഴി ഇതിനടുത്തുള്ള പൊഴിയൂര്‍ർ എന്ന് സ്ഥലത്താണ്. ബഹുഭൂരിപക്ഷം ജനങ്ങളും മത്സ്യബന്ധനം ഒരു ജീവണമാർഗം ആയി കണ്ടു മുന്നോട്ട് പോകുന്നു.</description></item><item><title>EIA and mailto</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/mailto/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 09:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/mailto/</guid><description>ഇത് അതല്ല വളരെ വൈകി വന്ന വിവേകം പോലെയാണ് EIA- 2020നു എതിരെ ഉയർന്ന പ്രതിഷേധം. ഓഗസ്റ്റ് 11 നു അവസാന തിയതി എന്ന് വന്നപ്പോൾ, സോഷ്യൽ മീഡിയയും മാധ്യമങ്ങളും എന്തിനു രാഷ്ട്രീയ നേതൃത്വം വരെ ഉണർന്നു. ഇവിടെ EIA 2020 യെ പറ്റി അല്ല പകരം അവിടെ തരംഗമായ https://environmentnetworkindia.github.io/ എന്നൊരു സൈറ്റ് നിങ്ങളിൽ പലരും കണ്ടിട്ടുണ്ടാകും. ഒറ്റ ക്ലിക്കിൽ ഇതാ, അതാതു മന്ത്രാലയത്തിന് മെയിൽ അയയ്ക്കാൻ ഇന്ദ്രജാലം പോലെ നിങ്ങളെ കൊണ്ട് പോകുന്നു. മലയാളം, ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് എന്ന് വേണ്ട ഒട്ടുമിക്ക ഭാഷകളിലും മെയിൽ തയ്യാർ. ഇവിടെ നിങ്ങളെ അതിനു സഹായിച്ച ഒരു ടെക്‌നിക്‌ ആണ് mailto (ഇതേ പേരിൽ ഒരു സ്ഥലം അങ്ങ് ഇറ്റലിയിൽ ഉണ്ട് , ഇത് അതല്ല ).</description></item><item><title>Pandemic times</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 20:39:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2020/</guid><description>Year of Uncertainity “Out of the void and vastness of the cosmos, life emerges; audacious, improbable. You and I are here. No other miracle is needed.” ― John Mark Green</description></item><item><title>Beginners guide to ERDAS IMAGINE</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/erdas-imagine-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 17:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/erdas-imagine-for-beginners/</guid><description>During the course period of GIS in kariavattom, we colleagues created a tutorial on Erdas Imagine, a remote sensing tool. The whole project was bounded to the syllabus and are extremely useful. Later I thought it would be beneficial to the beginners if the work is available as a website. If you find this useful share it with your friends.
Beginners guide to ERDAS IMAGINE</description></item><item><title>മൺറോ തുരുത്തിൽ ഒരു പകൽ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/munroe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 18:03:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/munroe/</guid><description>കൊല്ലം ജില്ലയുടെ തെക്കേയറ്റത്തു അഷ്ടമുടിക്കായലിന്റെ ഓരത്തുള്ള ഒരു തുരുത്താണ് മൺറോ തുരുത്ത്. ഒരു പക്ഷെ വർഷങ്ങളായി അവിടെ പോകണം , ചുരുങ്ങിയത് ഒരു പകൽ ചെലവഴിക്കണം എന്നത് ഒരാഗ്രഹമായി തുടർന്നു . കാര്യവട്ടം ക്യാമ്പസ്സിൽ ഒരു ഡിപ്ലോമ ചെയ്തുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുമ്പോഴാണ് ഒടുവിൽ ആ അവസരം ഒത്തുവന്നത് . അവിടെ പ്രോജക്ടിന്റെ ഭാഗമായി ഒരു ഫീൽഡ് സർവെയ്‌ക്കു പോകേണ്ടത് ആവശ്യവുമായിരുന്നു.
ഞങ്ങൾ നാലുപേർ ചേർന്നാണ് യാത്ര പോയത്. ഇതിൽ കൊല്ലംകാരിയായ ശരണ്യ മാത്രമായിരുന്നു ഏക സ്ത്രീ സാന്നിദ്ധ്യം. ബാക്കിയുള്ളവർ തിരുവന്തപുരത്തുകാരായ ഞാനും സാഹിബും ആദർശും. തലേദിനം തീരുമാനിച്ച യാത്ര ആയതിനാൽ വിശദമായ ഒരു യാത്ര പ്ലാൻ ഒന്നും ഉണ്ടായിരുന്നില്ല. എങ്കിലും വരുന്നത് വരുന്നിടത്തു വച്ച് കാണാം എന്ന മട്ടിൽ തന്നെയാണ് പുറപ്പെട്ടത്.</description></item><item><title>Linux DD commands മലയാളയത്തിൽ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/dd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 19:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/dd/</guid><description>നിങ്ങൾ ഒരു ലിന്ക്സ് OS ആണ് ഇപ്പോൾ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതെങ്കിൽ തീർച്ചയായും തുടർന്ന് വായിക്കുക. ഒരു OS ൽ നിന്നും മറ്റൊരു OS ലേക്ക് (ഉദാഹരണത്തിന് Ubuntu ൽ നിന്നും Linux mint ലേക്ക് ) കൂടുമാറാൻ പ്ലാൻ ചെയ്യുമ്പോൾ ആദ്യം ചെയ്യേണ്ടത് ആവശ്യമുള്ള .iso ഡൌൺലോഡ് ചെയ്തു ആത് bootable രൂപത്തിൽ ആക്കുക എന്നതാണ് . അതിനായി dd command ഇല്ലാതെ തന്നെ GUI അപ്പുകൾ ഉപയോഗിച്ചും ചെയ്യാവുന്നതാണ് ( Rufus ). ഇവിടെ terminal വഴി dd command ഉപയോഗിച്ച് ചെയ്യാവുന്ന ഒരു രീതിയാണ് താഴെ പറയുന്നത്.
File manager ൽ പോയി USB കാണിക്കുന്ന option ൽ right ക്ലിക്ക് ചെയ്തു unmount option തിരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുക .</description></item><item><title>ആപ്പ് ഇൻസ്റ്റാൾ ചെയ്യാതെയും കാണാം Comet Neowise</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/stellarium-web/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:00:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/stellarium-web/</guid><description>Sky safari ഉപയോഗിച്ച് comet neowise എങ്ങനെ കാണാം എന്നു മുൻപത്തെ ബ്ലോഗ്ഗിൽ നാം കണ്ടതാണല്ലോ. ചിലർക്കെങ്കിലും ആപ്പ് ഒക്കെ ഇൻസ്റ്റാൾ ചെയ്ത് കൊമെറ്റിനെ കാണാൻ മടിയായിരിക്കും. അങ്ങനെ ഉള്ള അന്വേഷണം എത്തി ചേർന്നത് open source planetarium ഭീമനായ Stellarium -ന്റെ website -ൽ ആണ്. അവരുടെ തന്നെ web ആപ്പ് ആണ് നമ്മുടെ സമസ്യക്കുള്ള ഉത്തരം.
Stellarium website https://stellarium-web.org/
ഈ website എല്ലാത്തരം operating system -ലും ഒരു പോലെ ഉപയോഗിക്കാവുന്നതാണ്.അതുകൊണ്ട് തന്നെ മൊബൈലിൽ ഈസിയായി എപ്പോൾ വേണമെങ്കിലും ഇന്റെർനെറ്റിന്റെ സഹായത്തോടെ ഉപയോഗിക്കാം.
എങ്ങനെ ഉപയോഗിക്കാം ? ആദ്യം തന്നെ https://stellarium-web.org/ സന്ദർശിക്കുക. നിങ്ങൾ മൊബൈലിൽ ആണ് എടുക്കുന്നതെങ്കിൽ location access അവർ ചോദിക്കും.</description></item><item><title>Comet Neowise (C/2020 F3)</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/neowise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 12:00:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/neowise/</guid><description>Neowise അടുത്ത 6800 വർഷത്തേക്ക് നമ്മുടെ അടുത്ത് വരാൻ സാധ്യത ഇല്ലാത്ത എന്നാൽ ഇപ്പോൾ കാണാൻ കഴിയുന്നതുമായ ഒരു കോമെറ്റ് ആണ് C/2020 F3 അഥവാ Neowise. അതായത് ഇപ്പൊ കണ്ടില്ലേൽ പിന്നെ ഇല്ല. ഉത്തരധ്രുവത്തിൽ മാത്രമേ ഈ കൊമെറ്റിനെ കാണാൻ കഴിയുകയുള്ളൂ .
Comet NEOWISE was first discovered in March by the infrared-optimized NEOWISE spacecraft (the name is short for Near-Earth Object Wide-field Infrared Space Explorer)1.
കൂടുതൽ അറിയാം : explainedinmalayalam.com
എപ്പോൾ, എവിടെ കാണാം ? ജൂലൈ 14 മുതൽ, 20 ദിവസം സൂര്യൻ അസ്തമിച്ചു ഒരു ഇരുപത് മിനുട്ട് നമുക്ക് നഗ്ന നേത്രം കൊണ്ട് തന്നെ കാണാനാകും.</description></item><item><title>Creating a simple corona virus model using blender</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/covid_blender/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 18:06:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/covid_blender/</guid><description>Blender-ൽ ഒരു കൊറോണ വൈറസ് ചുമ്മാ internet-ൽ തപ്പി നേരം പോയിരിക്കുമ്പോൾ ആണ് ഒരു ചിന്ത പെട്ടെന്ന് വന്നത് (ചിന്താ ജെറോം അല്ല ഇതു വേറെ). Blender എന്നൊരു software ഉണ്ട് നിങ്ങളിൽ പലർക്കും അറിയാവുന്നതായിരിക്കും എന്നാലും ഈ blender, 3D animations ഒക്കെ ഉണ്ടാക്കുവാനുള്ള ഒരു അടിപൊളി Free &amp;amp; open source software(FOSS) ആണ്. സത്യം പറഞ്ഞാൽ അതിന്റെ ABCD എനിക്ക് അറിയില്ലായിരുന്നു ഈ ചിന്ത ഉണ്ടാകും വരെ. ഒരു കുഞ്ഞൻ കൊറോണയേ blender ൽ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയാൽ ആത് ഒരു രസം തന്നെ. പക്ഷേ youtube -ൽ നോക്കിയപ്പോൾ item അവിടുണ്ട്. ഞാനായിട്ട് ഒരു പുതുമയും ഇവിടെ കൊടുക്കുന്നില്ല പകരം ഞാൻ നിർമിച്ച രസികൻ കൊറോണയെ ഇവിടെ പങ്കുവെക്കാം.</description></item><item><title>How to create a microgreen recipe</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/microgreen_experiment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 18:28:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/microgreen_experiment/</guid><description>മാധ്യമങ്ങളിൽ കണ്ട് പരിചയിച്ച ഒരു പേരാണ് Microgreen. ഇത്രക്ക് പറഞ്ഞുകേട്ട സ്ഥിതിക്ക് ഒന്നു നോക്കിക്കളയാം.
Microgreen? ഏകദേശം 1–3 ഇഞ്ച് (2.5–7.5 സെ.മീ) ഉയരമുള്ള ഇളം പച്ചക്കറി പച്ചിലകളാണ് മൈക്രോഗ്രീനുകൾ.ഇവ പാചകത്തിനും ശരീരത്തിനും ഉത്തമം.വെറും ഒരാഴ്ച്ച പരിശ്രമിച്ചാൽ രുചികരവും പോഷക സമൃദ്ധമായ ഒരു ഇലക്കറി ഉണ്ടാക്കി എടുക്കാം . Microgreen ഉണ്ടാക്കാൻ ആവശ്യമായത് ഒരു ചെറിയ പാത്രവും കുറച്ച് വിത്തുകളുമാണു. പയർ,ഗ്രീൻപീസ്,ഉലുവ പോലെ വേഗം മുളക്കുന്ന വിത്തുകൾ ഉത്തമം.
Nutritional value Among the 25 microgreens tested, red cabbage, cilantro, garnet amaranth, and green daikon radish had the highest concentrations of vitamin C, carotenoids, vitamin K, and vitamin E, respectively.</description></item><item><title>How to add audio in hugo static site using a shortcode.</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/audio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/audio/</guid><description>This is a simple tutorial on how to add audio files in hugo static sites via shortcodes. Just follow these steps
STEP 1 Create a file audio.html in layouts/shortcodes folder.
STEP 2 Add following lines of code in the newly created audio.html file and save.
STEP 3 Save the required audio file in /static/xxx . For the demonstrative purpose I put the sample audio file in /static/posts/shortcodes/ (That&amp;rsquo;s where I put my static files for shortcode demonstrating articles).</description></item><item><title>Covid19 kerala database</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/covid_database/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 22:17:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/covid_database/</guid><description>Live Covid19 patient database of kerala Google sheet database with regular updates
SOURCE: https://covid19kerala.info/
For detailed infographics visit above website. This is an open source project which is cloned from Covid19japan 1 and Maintained by Volunteers at CODD-K Team. Supported by Government College Kasaragod. Also available in both malayalam and english languages.
Rshiny apps Covid19japan&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>Dabbawala and the lunchbox</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/dabbawala/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:48:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/dabbawala/</guid><description>ധബ്ബാവാല ( Dabbawala) &amp;rsquo; ധബ്ബാവാല &amp;rsquo; എന്ന് എപ്പോഴെങ്കിലും കേട്ടിട്ടുണ്ടോ? മുംബൈ നഗരത്തിന്റെ സിരകളിൽ ഒഴുകി നടക്കുന്ന അല്ലെങ്കിൽ ജനങ്ങളെ കോർത്തിണക്കുന്ന ഒരു പ്രധാന കണ്ണിയാണ് ഈ ധബ്ബാവാല. തിരക്കിന്റെയും വേഗത്തിന്റെയും കാര്യത്തിൽ മുംബൈ വളരെ മുന്നിലാണ് . ആർക്കും നേരമില്ല ! സബർബ്ബൻ തീവണ്ടികൾ ഓടിപ്പിടിക്കുക ചില്ലറ കളിയല്ല . അത്രക്കും തിരക്കു പിടിച്ച നഗരത്തിൽ ഉച്ചയൂണും കൊണ്ടേ രാവിലെ വീട്ടിൽ നിന്നും ഇറങ്ങൂ എന്ന് വാശിപിടിക്കാൻ പറ്റില്ലല്ലോ. അവിടെയാണ് ഈ ധബ്ബവാലയുടെ റോൾ.
ഡബ്ബാവാല എന്നാൽ ഹിന്ദിയിലും മറാഠിയിലും “ഡബ്ബ (പാത്രം) കൊണ്ട് നടക്കുന്നയാൾ” എന്നാണ് അർത്ഥം. ഉച്ചഭക്ഷണത്തിനു ടിഫ്ഫിൻ എന്നും പേരുള്ളതിനാൽ, ഡബ്ബാവാലകളെ ടിഫ്ഫിൻവാലകൾ എന്നും വിളിക്കാറുണ്ട്.</description></item><item><title>പൊടിതട്ടിയെടുത്ത ഒരു സ്കൂൾ ഗ്രൂപ്പ് ഫോട്ടോ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/class_vii_a/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 20:09:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/class_vii_a/</guid><description>പുറത്ത് പൊടിപ്പിടിച്ച് കിടന്ന പുസ്തക കൂട്ടം ഒക്കെ നേരെയാക്കാം എന്ന് കരുതിയാണ് രാവിലെ ഒരു തൂവാലയും എടുത്തു മുഖം മറച്ചു ഇറങ്ങിത്തിരിച്ചത്. മൊത്തം പഴയ പുസ്തകങ്ങൾ, ആവശ്യം ഒട്ടുമില്ലാത്ത കുറെ പേപ്പർ കൂമ്പാരം ഒക്കെ പൊടിപ്പിടിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന അവസ്ഥയിലും. അങ്ങനെ അതിനെ ഒരു വഴിക്കാക്കി വന്നപ്പോഴാണ് ദേ കിടന്നുന്നു പഴയ ഒരു സ്കൂൾ ഗ്രൂപ്പ് ഫോട്ടോ. ആദ്യമേ സൂചിപ്പിച്ചതു പോലെ തന്നെ ഏഴാം ക്ലാസ്സിലെ ഒരേയൊരു തിരുശേഷിപ്പായിരുന്നു ആത് . മാരായമുട്ടം സ്കൂളിലെ ആ പഴയ കാലം ഒർമവന്നു. ഞങ്ങളുടെ ക്ലാസ്സിന്റെ ചുമതല ബിജു സാ‍റിനായിരുന്നു. അദ്ദേഹം അതെ സ്കൂളിൽ തന്നെയാണ് ഇപ്പോഴും. മികച്ച ഒരു ശാസ്ത്ര അധ്യാപകൻ എന്നതിലുപരി കുട്ടികളോട് ഒരു അധ്യാപകൻ എങ്ങനെ ആകണം എന്നതിന്റെ ഏറ്റവും നല്ല ഉദാഹരണം തന്നെയാണ് ബിജു സാർ.</description></item><item><title>രണ്ടു കാക്കകൾ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/two_crows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 18:51:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/two_crows/</guid><description>ഇൻഡ്യയിൽ രണ്ടു തരം കാക്കകൾ ആണ് പൊതുവേ കാണാറ്.
House crow (Corvus splendens) Jungle Crow (Corvus culminatus) കാണാനും ഇവർക്ക് ചില സാമ്യങ്ങളും വ്യത്യാസങ്ങളും ഉണ്ട്. ചുരുക്കി പറഞ്ഞാൽ ഒന്നു ഫ്രീക്ക് മറ്റേത് മൊട്ട. ഇതിൽ ഒന്നാമത്തെ കൂട്ടരാണ് ഈ കഥയിൽ ഉള്ളത് .
സംഭവം നടക്കുന്നത് കുറച്ച് മാസങ്ങൾക്ക് മുൻപാണ്. പെട്ടന്ന് ഒരു സുപ്രഭാതത്തിൽ ആണ് എനിക്ക് വെളുപ്പിനു എണീറ്റ് ഓടിയാൽ കൊള്ളാമെന്നും അങ്ങനെ ചെയ്താൽ എന്റെ ആരോഗ്യം ഒക്കെ കൂട്ടിക്കളയാം എന്നും തോന്നിയത്. തീർത്തും നല്ലൊരു ആശയം തന്നെ. അങ്ങനെ ഒന്നു രണ്ടു ആഴ്ചത്തെ കഠിനമായ പരിശ്രമഫലമായി ഞാൻ വെളുപ്പിനു കേൾക്കുന്ന അലാറം ഓഫ് ആക്കാതിരിക്കൻ പഠിച്ചു.</description></item><item><title>Adding a leaflet map with a popup</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/sample_leaflet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/sample_leaflet/</guid><description>Map with a popup! Below map is embedded in this post with the help of shortcode created by Simonfrey which uses OSM and Leaflet. A popup is added like a cherry on the top of a cake. Placing layout/shortcode in /themes folder was an issue in the beginning. Later this folder is moved into the root folder of this blog. This change practically resolved the issue with adaptability of leaflet shortcode.</description></item><item><title>COVID 19 തൽസമയ ഭൂപടം</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/covid19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/covid19/</guid><description>ലോകത്തെ പിടിച്ചു കുലുക്കുന്ന ഒരു മഹാമാരിയായി COVID19 മാറിക്കഴിഞ്ഞിരിക്കുന്നു.
The 2019–20 coronavirus outbreak is an ongoing global outbreak of coronavirus disease 2019 that has been declared a Public Health Emergency of International Concern. It is caused by the SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus, first identified in Wuhan, Hubei, China. 1
തൽസമയ ഭൂപടങ്ങൾ തൽസമയ ഭൂപടങ്ങൾ നമ്മൾ പ്രകൃതി ദുരന്തങ്ങളിൽ ഉപയോഗിച്ചു കണ്ടിട്ട്ള്ളതാണു ഇപ്പോൾ പകർന്നു വ്യാപിക്കുന്ന COVID19 അതിന്റെ വ്യാപന നിരക്ക് ,അതിന്റെ സഞ്ചാരപാത ഒക്കെ ഈ ഭൂപടത്തിൽ കൂടെ മനസിലാക്കുവാൻ കഴിയും.
Coronavirus COVID-19 Global Cases by Johns Hopkins CSSE കൂട്ടത്തിൽ ആധികാരികവും മാപ്പിങ് Desktop/Mobile പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോർമിനും ഒരുപോലെ ലഭ്യമാക്കിയിരിക്കുന്നതു Coronavirus COVID-19 Global Cases by Johns Hopkins CSSE ആണ്.</description></item><item><title>എങ്ങനെ ഞാൻ ഡയറി എഴുതിത്തുടങ്ങി ?</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/why-diary/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/why-diary/</guid><description>ഇതിപ്പോ എന്താ കഥ ഒരു ഡയറി എഴുതുന്നത് ഇപ്പൊ വല്യ കാര്യം ആണോ? എന്നാൽ കാര്യം നിസ്സാരമല്ല . ഒന്നാമത്തെ കാര്യം ഇക്കണ്ട വർഷങ്ങൾ ഡയറി എഴുത്തു ശീലം ഇല്ല എന്നത് തന്നെ . ശീലങ്ങൾ തുടങ്ങാൻ എളുപ്പമാണ് പലപ്പോഴും . എന്നാൽ ആ ശീലങ്ങൾ ഒരു ദിനചര്യ ആക്കി മാറ്റാൻ നമ്മൾ ഒന്ന് മെനക്കെടേണ്ടി വരും .അപ്പൊ പറഞ്ഞു വന്നത് ഡയറി എഴുതുന്ന കാര്യം . നാട്ടിലുള്ളോരൊക്കെ പുതിയ വർഷത്തെ എതിരേൽക്കാൻ ഓരോ &amp;ldquo;resolution&amp;rdquo; എടുത്തിട്ടുണ്ടല്ലോ എന്നാൽ എനിക്കും വേണം എന്നായി ഞാനും . ഇത് വളരെ വര്ഷങ്ങള്ക്കു മുന്നേ തുടങ്ങിയ ചിന്തയാണ് . എന്റെ സ്വപ്നം സാഫല്യമാക്കാൻ ഇത്രെയും കലാം തടസ്സം നിന്ന രണ്ടുപേരിൽ ഒരാൾ എന്റെ &amp;ldquo;മടി &amp;quot; തന്നെ എന്നാൽ കുറ്റകരമാവണം മാലോകരെ അതായതു സാധാരണ മനുഷ്യരെ ഡയറി എഴുതാൻ പ്രേരിപ്പിക്കാത്തതു ഡയറി പബ്ലിഷേഴ്സ് ആണ് .</description></item><item><title>Moments to cherish</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 20:39:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/galleries/2019/</guid><description>Joyful times “I have realized that the past and future are real illusions, that they exist in the present, which is what there is and all there is.” ― Alan Wilson Watts</description></item><item><title>Photographic experiments</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2019/photography/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2019/photography/</guid><description>Photography is the art of freezing the present for the future. The creative side of the photographer makes the photographs a valuable property. Basically one can argue that a good photograph is born irrespective of the device it shoot. But technically quality stuffs need quality gadgets. Checkout my latest photographs in Gallery section</description></item><item><title>Me ?</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/about/</guid><description>I’m Arun Gopinath. An enthusiastic person who loves travelling and photography. A human being who believes technology is meant to save nature and not to destroy it.
I learned Physics and Geographic Information System. Always believe learning is fun.
Contact me You can find me on Github and Gitlab. Also feel free to e-mail for any enquires. You can find me in Telegram also.
My projects Below is an incomplete list of projects I worked on.</description></item><item><title>Tidy tuesday tweets</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tidy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tidy/</guid><description>A weekly social data project in R A weekly data project aimed at the R ecosystem. As this project was borne out of the R4DS Online Learning Community and the R for Data Science textbook, an emphasis was placed on understanding how to summarize and arrange data to make meaningful charts with ggplot2, tidyr, dplyr, and other tools in the tidyverse ecosystem. However, any code-based methodology is welcome - just please remember to share the code used to generate the results1.</description></item></channel></rss>