<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GIS on Arun Gopinath</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/gis/</link><description>Recent content in GIS on Arun Gopinath</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/gis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QGIS model to quickly calculate bound box of all polygons in a shapefile</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/qgis_bound_box_model/qgis_bound_box_model/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/qgis_bound_box_model/qgis_bound_box_model/</guid><description>Calculating the boundary box of a large number of polygons in a shapefile in QGIS is discussed earlier in this post. The process itself is tedious and required a support from Microsoft Office. There has been numerous updates arrived in QGIS and several algorithms were incorporated. Keeping this in mind I developed a QGIS model which can create an output with a simple click.
Download this Model and save it in suitable location.</description></item><item><title>Convert a shapefile into a interactive online map</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/maps-online/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 17:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/maps-online/</guid><description>Introduction Imagine you have a shapefile (.shp) with you. Now you want to show the interactive map to your colleague. There are two options:
Share your shapefile via e-mail OR
Share as a link (more user friendly). Not everytime you are equipped with ArcGIS or QGIS. Its difficult to open those files in your mobile devices. So a easy link which opens an interactive map will be cool idea to checkout.</description></item><item><title>Extracting the boundary extends of polygons in a shapefile using QGIS and VBA in Microsoft excel</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/bound-extend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/bound-extend/</guid><description>Introduction In this tutorial lets us learn how to extract the boundary limits or bbox values of each polygon in a shapefile using QGIS. First of all, imagine a shapefile consists of some number of polygons. So each polygon can be exactly fit into imaginary rectangles each having upper and lower limits of latitude and longitude values. These four limits will be the boundary for that polygon. Similarly, remaining polygons will also have such boundaries.</description></item><item><title>Beginners guide to ERDAS IMAGINE</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/erdas-imagine-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 17:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/erdas-imagine-for-beginners/</guid><description>During the course period of GIS in kariavattom, we colleagues created a tutorial on Erdas Imagine, a remote sensing tool. The whole project was bounded to the syllabus and are extremely useful. Later I thought it would be beneficial to the beginners if the work is available as a website. If you find this useful share it with your friends.
Beginners guide to ERDAS IMAGINE</description></item></channel></rss>