<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Arun Gopinath</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Arun Gopinath</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Convert a bulk of pdf files into images in just two lines of code (Only for linux users)</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-07-31-convert-a-bulk-of-pdf-into-images-in-two-lines-of-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-07-31-convert-a-bulk-of-pdf-into-images-in-two-lines-of-code/</guid><description>Just two lines of code for linux users Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a folder consists of hundreds of pdf files. Your job is to convert it into image format (jpg or png). If you are in a Linux environment, then the solution is pretty simple. Just two lines of code!
In the file manager open the folder containing pdf files. Right-click and select Open terminal (here). Once inside that directory,then you can type or copy and paste the following command in the terminal and press enter:</description></item><item><title>Linux DD commands മലയാളയത്തിൽ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/dd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 19:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/dd/</guid><description>നിങ്ങൾ ഒരു ലിന്ക്സ് OS ആണ് ഇപ്പോൾ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതെങ്കിൽ തീർച്ചയായും തുടർന്ന് വായിക്കുക. ഒരു OS ൽ നിന്നും മറ്റൊരു OS ലേക്ക് (ഉദാഹരണത്തിന് Ubuntu ൽ നിന്നും Linux mint ലേക്ക് ) കൂടുമാറാൻ പ്ലാൻ ചെയ്യുമ്പോൾ ആദ്യം ചെയ്യേണ്ടത് ആവശ്യമുള്ള .iso ഡൌൺലോഡ് ചെയ്തു ആത് bootable രൂപത്തിൽ ആക്കുക എന്നതാണ് . അതിനായി dd command ഇല്ലാതെ തന്നെ GUI അപ്പുകൾ ഉപയോഗിച്ചും ചെയ്യാവുന്നതാണ് ( Rufus ). ഇവിടെ terminal വഴി dd command ഉപയോഗിച്ച് ചെയ്യാവുന്ന ഒരു രീതിയാണ് താഴെ പറയുന്നത്.
File manager ൽ പോയി USB കാണിക്കുന്ന option ൽ right ക്ലിക്ക് ചെയ്തു unmount option തിരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുക .</description></item></channel></rss>