<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>QGIS on Arun Gopinath</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/qgis/</link><description>Recent content in QGIS on Arun Gopinath</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/qgis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QGIS model to quickly calculate bound box of all polygons in a shapefile</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/qgis_bound_box_model/qgis_bound_box_model/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/qgis_bound_box_model/qgis_bound_box_model/</guid><description>Calculating the boundary box of a large number of polygons in a shapefile in QGIS is discussed earlier in this post. The process itself is tedious and required a support from Microsoft Office. There has been numerous updates arrived in QGIS and several algorithms were incorporated. Keeping this in mind I developed a QGIS model which can create an output with a simple click.
Download this Model and save it in suitable location.</description></item><item><title>Extracting the boundary extends of polygons in a shapefile using QGIS and VBA in Microsoft excel</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/bound-extend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:05:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/bound-extend/</guid><description>Introduction In this tutorial lets us learn how to extract the boundary limits or bbox values of each polygon in a shapefile using QGIS. First of all, imagine a shapefile consists of some number of polygons. So each polygon can be exactly fit into imaginary rectangles each having upper and lower limits of latitude and longitude values. These four limits will be the boundary for that polygon. Similarly, remaining polygons will also have such boundaries.</description></item></channel></rss>