<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>infographics on Arun Gopinath</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/infographics/</link><description>Recent content in infographics on Arun Gopinath</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/infographics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is Cristiano Ronaldo lost his interest in twitter? A fun analysis of tweets of Cristiano Ronaldo using R</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-11-21-a-fun-analysis-of-tweets-of-cristiano-ronaldo-in-r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-11-21-a-fun-analysis-of-tweets-of-cristiano-ronaldo-in-r/</guid><description>A detailed analysis of tweets of famous footballer Cristiano Ronaldo in R Get Ronaldo’s tweets timeline Let’s dive into it. Plotting tweets per months over the time period Bar plot to get more insight Is there any pattern over the months ? What about over the days ? Tweets over the time Retweets v/s Original tweets Text mining - Let’s deep dive into the tweet data What about Hashtags frequency ?</description></item><item><title>Exploratory Data Analysis of Covid 19 data of India</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/data-exploration-of-covid-19-data-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/data-exploration-of-covid-19-data-india/</guid><description>Exploring and visualising Covid 19 dataset of Indian states using R Load required packages Data… Data.. Loading latest shapefile of Indian states Exploratory Data Analysis First reporting case - When ? Where ? Peak active covid case in India - When ? Which day records maximum TPR in India? Highest death rate recorded ? Top 5 states with cumulative confirmed cases ? Least cumulative confirmed cases ? Most deaths - Top 5 ?</description></item><item><title>Detailed map of Kerala assembly elections 2021</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/assembly2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/assembly2021/</guid><description>Kerala assembly election results 2021 The 2021 Kerala Legislative Assembly election was held in Kerala on 6 April 2021 to elect 140 members to the 15th Kerala Legislative Assembly. The results declared on 2 May.
Results in a nut shell Party Seats LDF 99 UDF 41 NDA Nil Total seats 140 This article provides the shapefile containing the details of candidates in each legislative assembly. Shapefile used here are obtained from Kerala Open Data.</description></item><item><title>പെരുങ്കടവിള തദ്ദേശ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പിന്റെ ചില സ്ഥിതി വിവര കണക്കുകൾ</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/election2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/thoughts/2020/election2020/</guid><description>പെരുങ്കടവിള തദ്ദേശ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പിന്റെ ചില സ്ഥിതി-വിവര കണക്കുകൾ 2020-ലെ കേരളം തദ്ദേശ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പിന്റെ ആവേശം ഉൾക്കൊണ്ട് എന്റെ പഞ്ചായത്തായ പെരുങ്കടവിളയിലെ ചില രസകരമായ തിരഞ്ഞെടുപ്പ് വസ്തുതകളാണ് ഈ ലേഖനത്തിൽ. ഈ അന്വേഷണത്തിൽ പഞ്ചായത്തിലെ 16 വാർഡുകളുടെ വിവരങ്ങൾ ആണ് ഉൾക്കൊള്ളിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നത്. ത്രിതല ഭരണ സംവിധാനത്തിൽ മുകൾ തട്ടായ ബ്ലോക്ക് ഡിവിഷനും ജില്ലാ ഡിവിഷനും ഇതിൽ ഉൾപ്പെടുത്തിയിട്ടില്ല .
Total available votes: 20495
പഞ്ചായത്ത് ഭൂപടം
വാർഡുകൾ ഭൂപടം - സർക്കാർ വക
സ്ഥാനാർത്ഥികൾ - ചില രസകരമായ വിവരങ്ങൾ വിവരശേഖരണം കേരളം സ്റ്റേറ്റ് ഇലെക്ഷൻ കമ്മീഷന്റെ വെബ്‌സൈറ്റ് വഴി ഡൌൺലോഡ് ചെയ്തെടുക്കൽ ആയിരുന്നു ആദ്യപടി. പതിനാറു വാർഡിലെയും സ്ഥാനാർത്ഥികൾ അവരുടെ - പേര് , വിലാസം , പ്രായം , പാർട്ടി, ചിഹ്നം, ലിംഗം തുടങ്ങിയ അടിസ്ഥാന വിവരങ്ങൾ ആണ് അതിൽ കാണാനാവുക.</description></item></channel></rss>