<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R on Arun Gopinath</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/r/</link><description>Recent content in R on Arun Gopinath</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arungopi.gitlab.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a rainfall forecasting dashboard of Kerala, India. A non-shiny dashboard for all seasons.</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2022-03-03-creating-a-rainfall-forecasting-dashboard-of-kerala-india-a-non-shiny-dashboard-for-all-seasons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2022-03-03-creating-a-rainfall-forecasting-dashboard-of-kerala-india-a-non-shiny-dashboard-for-all-seasons/</guid><description>A non-shiny dashboard for all seasons Ideas and implemenation Let’s dive in Part 1 - Tabulizer helps but.. Part 2 - Flexdashboard and leaflet is a great combo. Part 3 - Automation using Github actions. A non-shiny dashboard for all seasons Dashboards are exciting tools to present an idea in the most human-friendly form available. Ideas are infectious it took some time to fix the theme of my dashboard will be ‘Rainfall forecast of Kerala’.</description></item><item><title>Is Cristiano Ronaldo lost his interest in twitter? A fun analysis of tweets of Cristiano Ronaldo using R</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-11-21-a-fun-analysis-of-tweets-of-cristiano-ronaldo-in-r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/2021-11-21-a-fun-analysis-of-tweets-of-cristiano-ronaldo-in-r/</guid><description>A detailed analysis of tweets of famous footballer Cristiano Ronaldo in R Get Ronaldo’s tweets timeline Let’s dive into it. Plotting tweets per months over the time period Bar plot to get more insight Is there any pattern over the months ? What about over the days ? Tweets over the time Retweets v/s Original tweets Text mining - Let’s deep dive into the tweet data What about Hashtags frequency ?</description></item><item><title>Exploratory Data Analysis of Covid 19 data of India</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/data-exploration-of-covid-19-data-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/data-exploration-of-covid-19-data-india/</guid><description>Exploring and visualising Covid 19 dataset of Indian states using R Load required packages Data… Data.. Loading latest shapefile of Indian states Exploratory Data Analysis First reporting case - When ? Where ? Peak active covid case in India - When ? Which day records maximum TPR in India? Highest death rate recorded ? Top 5 states with cumulative confirmed cases ? Least cumulative confirmed cases ? Most deaths - Top 5 ?</description></item><item><title>Can you identify this legendary malayalam novel ? A ggwordcloud experiment in R</title><link>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/r-wordcloud/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arungopi.gitlab.io/post/tutorials/r-wordcloud/</guid><description>A legendary novel Yesterday out of nowhere the masterpiece novel, which changed the course of Malayalam literature forever pop up in my social media feed. After reading the digital copy (.epub) of the same, the idea for this article came into my mind. All I have for you is “words”.
Create a word cloud using R First of all, load necessary R packages. {readtext} and {tidytext} for load our novel.</description></item></channel></rss>